Guide to the Carl Van Vechten Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1907-1971; Series I; 79.8; 183 boxes
  - A-Z Correspondence
    - Pringle, Aileen
      - 1962-1971, undated (Box 130, Folder 1607-1613)
        Includes letter from Henry Daniell to Pringle (1962); postcards from Karl Priebe to Pringle, sent by Pringle to CVV (1962, 1963); letter from Bruce Kellner to Pringle, enclosed with letter from Pringle to CVV (1963); note from Mary Servoss to Pringle, enclosed with note from Pringle to CVV (1963); photograph of Pringle, enclosed with letter from Pringle to FM (1970)
      - Clipping, 1963 (Box 181 (Oversize), Folder 2319)
        Clipping from Life magazine, previously filed with envelope dated 1963 January 19
    - Productions, Inc. (Organization: Washington, D.C.)
      See: Kaufman, Edgar
    - Provincetown Players, 1916 (Box 130, Folder 1614)
    - Provincetown Playhouse (New York, N.Y.), 1924–1954 (Box 130, Folder 1615)
      Includes letter from Catherine Huntington to Alice B. Toklas (1954)
    - Psi Upsilon Fraternity, 1933–1964 (Box 130, Folder 1616)
    - Purdy, James
      Includes fictional correspondence, press releases, news bulletins, advice columns, advertisements, recipes, as well as poetry by Purdy
      - 1956 September–1957 May (Box 131, Folder 1617-1625)
        Includes photographs of Purdy, enclosed with letters from Purdy to CVV (1956-1957); photograph of unidentified child, enclosed with letter from Purdy to CVV (1957); letter from Jorma Jules Sjoblom to CVV (1957)
      - 1957 June–1957 October (Box 132, Folder 1626-1635)
        Includes letter from Jorma Jules Sjoblom to CVV (1957)
      - 1957 November–1958 December (Box 133, Folder 1636-1644)
        Includes photograph of a drawing of Purdy by Paul Swan (1957); draft of a letter from CVV in support of Purdy to the Guggenheim Foundation (1957)
      - 1959 January–1960 June (Box 134, Folder 1645-1656)
        Includes letter from Jorma Jules Sjoblom to CVV (1959); typescript transcript, carbon copy, English translation of a review from Die Welt, May 16, 1959, of Color of Darkness by Purdy, with inscription to CVV (1959); two letters from the publicity director of Farrar, Straus and Cudahy, Inc. Publishers to CVV (1959); typed transcription of letter, carbon copy, from John Farrar to Purdy, enclosed with letter from Purdy to CVV (1959); postcard from CVV to Purdy (1959); typed transcript of Dorothy Parker's review of Malcolm by Purdy which appeared in Esquire magazine, enclosed with letter from Purdy to CVV (1959); letter from Henry Allen Moe of the Guggenheim Foundation to CVV (1959)
      - 1960 July–1962 December (Box 135, Folder 1657-1665)
        Includes letter from Elsa Duval to CVV (1961); typescript mimeograph transcript of "The Zephyrs of Death" by Winfield Townley Scott, published in the New Republic, November 17, 1962, enclosed with letter from Purdy to CVV (1962); letter from Margaret T. Baker of Harvest Productions to CVV (1962)
      - 1963 January–1964 December, undated (Box 136, Folder 1666-1672)
        Includes three letters from Margaret T. Barker of Harvest Productions to CVV (1963); letter from Gordon N. Ray of the Guggenheim Foundation to CVV (1963); photograph of Purdy, enclosed with holiday card from Purdy to CVV (1964)
      - Clippings, 1964 (Box 181 (Oversize), Folder 2320)
        Oversize newspaper clippings about Purdy
    - Purvis, Donn, 1954; 1962 (Box 136, Folder 1673)
    - "Q" General, 1931; 1946 (Box 136, Folder 1674)
    - Queensberry, Douglas, Marquis of, 1911; undated (Box 136, Folder 1675)
    - "R" General
      - 1908-1964, undated (Box 137, Folder 1676-1681)
      - Newspaper clipping, 1935 November 19 (Box 182 (Oversize), Folder 2337)
        Clipping from the Nashville Banner, regarding Carl S. Raswan, with note from Raswan to CVV written on upper left-hand corner
    - Raison, Milton M. (Milton Michael), 1923–1924 (Box 137, Folder 1682)
    - Random House (Firm), 1934–1963 (Box 137, Folder 1683)
    - Raney, William E.
      - 1943 (Box 137, Folder 1684-1687)
      - 1944-1951, undated (Box 138, Folder 1688-1699)
        Includes photographic postcard of troops on a bus, with note from Raney to CVV (1945); gift acknowledgement from Yale University Library to Raney, with note from Raney to CVV (1947); typed letter, carbon copy, from Raney to Bill Robinson (1947); typed letters, carbon copies, from Raney to Donald Gallup, enclosed with letters from Raney to CVV (1947, 1948); typed letter, carbon copy, from Raney to Alice B. Toklas, enclosed with note to CVV (1948); typed letter, carbon copy, from Raney to Mrs. Arthur Davison Ficke (1948); typed letter, carbon copy, from Raney to Edgar Kaufman, enclosed with letter from Raney to CVV (1949); note from John Selby to CVV (1949); letter from John Hite to Raney, and letter, carbon copy, to Hite, enclosed with note from Raney to CVV (1949); letter from Hedgerow Theatre to Rinehart & Company, enclosed with letter from Raney to CVV (1949)
    - Rascoe, Burton, 1928–1942 (Box 139, Folder 1700)
    - Rathbone, Ouida, 1962–1967 (Box 139, Folder 1701)
      Includes cards co-signed by Rathbone's husband, Basil Rathbone
    - Rauzin, Julius, 1951–1964 (Box 139, Folder 1702)
      Includes photographic postcard of a cock fight, enclosed with letter from Rauzin to CVV (1952)
    - Rawlings, Marjorie Kinnan, 1948–1960 (Box 139, Folder 1703)
      Includes letter from E. J. Strong of the Los Angeles Times to CVV (1953); photograph of Rawlings, with note from Rawlings to CVV on verso (1953); note from Norton Baskin to CVV and FM (1954); two letters from Gordon E. Bigelow, University of Florida, to CVV (1960)
    - Redman, Ben Ray, 1931 (Box 139, Folder 1704)
      Telegram from Redman and wife, Frieda Redman to FM
    - Reed, Florence, 1932-1964, undated (Box 139, Folder 1705)
    - Reed, John, 1913; undated (Box 139, Folder 1706)
      Includes autograph manuscript stanzas, initialed JR, first line: "Deep in garden-gloom" (undated)
    - Reed, Susan, 1945–1963 (Box 139, Folder 1707)
    - Reedy's Mirror, 1918–1919 (Box 139, Folder 1708)
    - Reggie, Adriane, 1957 (Box 139, Folder 1709)
    - Rey, John B., 1951–1952 (Box 139, Folder 1710)
      Photographs of Rey and others, and photographic negatives "inspired by Peter Whiffle ," enclosed with letter from Rey to CVV (1951); "The Novels of Carl Van Vechten by John B. Rey," typescript essay, carbon copy, enclosed with letter from Rey to CVV (1951)
    - Rhodes, Donald E., 1963 (Box 139, Folder 1711)
    - Rhodias, Hans, 1958–1964 (Box 139, Folder 1712)
    - Rice, Elmer, 1934–1965 (Box 139, Folder 1713)
    - Richards, Bernard G., 1964–1965 (Box 139, Folder 1714)
    - Richards, Grant, 1923–1934 (Box 139, Folder 1715)
    - Richman, Arthur, 1930–1943 (Box 139, Folder 1716)
      Includes telegram to FM signed by Lilly Richman (1935)
    - Ridge, George Ross, 1962–1963 (Box 139, Folder 1717)
    - Rigdon, Walter, 1963 (Box 139, Folder 1718)
      Letters to and regarding FM
    - Riley, Condon, 1959–1960 (Box 139, Folder 1719)
    - Rinehart & Company, Inc., 1950–1967 (Box 139, Folder 1720)
      Includes letter from Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc. (1964)
    - Ringo, James, 1964 (Box 139, Folder 1721)
    - Rivera, Diego
      - 1932–1950 (Box 139, Folder 1722)
        Includes no correspondence with Diego Rivera; one letter from Carmen Rivera (1932); third-party letters regarding CVV's loan of a Rivera painting to an exhibition at the Instituto Nacional De Bellas Artes, Mexico City (1950)
      - Insurance policy, 1949 March 15 (Box 181 (Oversize), Folder 2321)
        Insurance policy covering painting owned by CVV, "El Copetón" by Rivera, while it was loaned to the Instituto Nacional de Bellas Artes, previously filed with letter from the director of the Insituto, dated 149 March 16
    - Roach, Steven W., 1917 (Box 139, Folder 1723)
      Letters to FM written for Roach by his nurse, Greta Orsell
    - Robb, Inez, 1961 (Box 139, Folder 1724)
    - Robinson, Forest, 1921; undated (Box 140, Folder 1725)
    - Rockwell, Kenneth, 1928-1951, undated (Box 140, Folder 1726)
    - Rodgers, Richard, 1965 January 12 (Box 140, Folder 1727)
    - Rodman, Selden, 1947–1960 (Box 140, Folder 1728)
    - Roeder, B. F., 1934 September 12 (Box 140, Folder 1729)
    - Roeder, Ralph, 1915 October 17 (Box 140, Folder 1730)
    - Roger, Brother, C.R., 1944 July 24 (Box 140, Folder 1731)
      Includes seven photographic postcards of African children and adults
    - Roger Kent, Inc.
      - Correspondence, 1948–1949 (Box 140, Folder 1732)
        Includes correspondence with Leo Perper and third-party correspondence regarding exhibition of CVV photographs
      - Exhibition lists, notes and clippings, 1949 (Box 140, Folder 1733)
    - Rogers, William G., 1935–1965 (Box 140, Folder 1734-1736)
      CVV letters to Rogers, gift of William G. Rogers, 1972
    - Ronayne, Mary, 1960 February 6 (Box 140, Folder 1737)
    - Ropa, Jerry, 1959–1960 (Box 140, Folder 1738)
    - Rorem, Ned, 1956–1960 (Box 140, Folder 1739)
    - Rose, Francis, Sir, 1937; 1948; undated (Box 140, Folder 1740)
    - Rose, Stuart, 1936–1958 (Box 140, Folder 1741)
    - Rosenberg, Marc L., 1962 (Box 140, Folder 1742)
    - Ross, Marvin Chauncey, 1934 (Box 140, Folder 1743)
    - Ross, Robert, 1938–1964 (Box 140, Folder 1744)
      Includes notes signed by Ross's wife, Margalo Gillmore Ross
    - Roth, Beulah Spigelgass, 1963 (Box 140, Folder 1745)
    - Rothschild, Howard, 1963; [1971?]; undated (Box 140, Folder 1746)
    - Rowe, Arthur, 1916 May 6 (Box 140, Folder 1747)
    - Royle, Edward Milton, [1918] (Box 140, Folder 1748)
    - Rubenstein, Helena, 1959–1964 (Box 140, Folder 1749)
    - Rumsey, John W., 1915 September 13 (Box 140, Folder 1750)
    - Russell, Kitty, 1950; undated (Box 140, Folder 1751)
    - Rutherford, Tom, 1928–1964 (Box 141, Folder 1752-1753)
    - Rutledge, Richard, 1952-1964, undated (Box 141, Folder 1754-1756)
      Includes photograph of Rutledge in Japan, enclosed with letter from Rutledge to CVV (1953)
    - "S" General, 1908-1964, undated (Box 142, Folder 1757-1768)
    - Saddler, Donald, 1930-1964, undated (Box 143, Folder 1769-1770)
      Includes Pearl Bailey's lipstick impression on letter from Saddler to CVV (1951)
    - Sagerson, 1920; 1922 (Box 143, Folder 1771)
    - Saks, Donald, 1926 (Box 143, Folder 1772)
    - Salemme, Antonio, 1929–1965 (Box 143, Folder 1773)
    - Saltus, Edgar, 1918; undated (Box 143, Folder 1774)
      Includes letter from CVV to Saltus
    - Saltus, Marie Giles, 1922-1923, undated (Box 143, Folder 1775)
      Includes holiday card with photograph of Saltus, a black woman, and two dogs (undated)
    - Salvation Army, 1967 November 2 (Box 143, Folder 1776)
    - Sanborn, Pitts, 1917–1922 (Box 143, Folder 1777)
    - Sanger, Margaret
      - 1960–1962 (Box 143, Folder 1778)
        Form letters regarding the World Population Emergency Campaign
      - World Population Emergency Campaign posters, 1960, 1962 (Box 182 (Oversize), Folder 2338)
        Reprints of advertisements for the World Population Emergency Campaign from the New York Times dated 1960 May 8, and 1962 February 27, previously enclosed with letters from Sanger to CVV dated 1960 October 17, and 1962 March 20
    - Saportas, Marion Tiffany, 1933-1952, undated (Box 143, Folder 1779)
    - Saroyan, William, 1962 December 28 (Box 143, Folder 1780)
    - Saturday Review, 1947–1967 (Box 143, Folder 1781)
    - Saul, Milton, 1949–1956 (Box 143, Folder 1782-1783)
      Includes photograph of a prospective home of Saul, enclosed with letter from Saul to CVV (1956); photograph of Saul's son, Mark Llewelyn Saul, enclosed with letter from Saul to CVV (1956)
    - Sawyer, Julian
      - 1939–1948 (Box 143, Folder 1784-1785)
      - 1949–1950 (Box 144, Folder 1786)
        Includes "Salmagundi of Sins," typescript review by Sawyer of Gertrude Stein: Form and Intelligibility, edited by Rosalind S. Miller (1949)
    - Scheff, Fritzi, 1943–1948 (Box 144, Folder 1787)
      Includes cancelled check to Scheff from CVV (1949)
    - Schmermund, Marie, 1960–1963 (Box 144, Folder 1788)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold, 1933 November 29 (Box 144, Folder 1789)
    - Schorer, Mark, 1959 (Box 144, Folder 1790)
    - Schwab, Arnold T., 1950–1963 (Box 144, Folder 1791)
      Includes reprint of Schwab's "James Huneker's Criticism of American Literature," from American Literature, March 1957, inscribed by Schwab to CVV (1957)
    - Schwartz, Milton, 1958–1964 (Box 144, Folder 1792)
    - Scofield, Paul, 1962 April 15 (Box 144, Folder 1793)
    - Scott, Zachary
      See also: Ford, Ruth
      - 1956-1964, undated (Box 144, Folder 1794-1795)
        Includes correspondence signed by Scott's wife, Ruth Ford; letter and note from daughter Shelley Scott to CVV and FM (1962)
      - Easter poster, 1963 (Box 181 (Oversize), Folder 2322)
        Reprint of a woodcut from a 19th century book of Russian popular prints, sent to CVV and FM by Zachary Scott and Ruth Ford at Easter, with envelope postmarked 1963 April 10
    - Seabrook, Katie, 1931–1935 (Box 144, Folder 1796)
      See also: Seabrook, William
    - Seabrook, William, 1929-1964, undated (Box 144, Folder 1797-1798)
      Includes notes signed by Seabrook's wives Katie Edmonson Seabrook, and Marjorie Worthington Seabrook; letter, carbon copy, from Seabrook to Ann Watkins, enclosed with letter from Seabrook to CVV (1938); letter, carbon copy, from Seabrook to F.D. Patterson of the George Washington Carver Foundation, with letter from Patterson to Seabrook (1943); photographic postcards of Seabrook's barn home in Rhinebeck, New York (undated)
    - Seiffert, Majorie Allen, 1925-1939, undated (Box 144, Folder 1799)
      Includes letter signed by Seiffert's husband, Otto Seiffert (1936)
    - Seitz, Royce, 1964 December 22 (Box 144, Folder 1800)
    - Seldes, Gilbert, 1931-1965, undated (Box 145, Folder 1801)
      Includes correspondence signed by Seldes' wife, Amanda Seldes
    - Seldes, Marian, 1944–1968 (Box 145, Folder 1802)
    - Sell, Henry Blackman, 1918–1919 (Box 145, Folder 1803)
      Includes four photographs of Sell's cat, enclosed with letter from Sell to CVV (1919)
    - Selwart, Tonio, 1931-1964, undated (Box 145, Folder 1804)
      Includes postcards co-signed by Alice de la Mar (1938); photographs of Selwart and friends (1931-1938, undated)
    - Selwyn, Edgar, 1926 July 22 (Box 145, Folder 1805)
    - Servoss, Mary, 1920-1965, undated (Box 145, Folder 1806)
    - The Seven Arts, 1916–1917 (Box 145, Folder 1807)
      Includes letters signed by Waldo Frank
    - Seymour, May Davenport, 1942-1965, undated (Box 145, Folder 1808-1811)
      Includes notes from Seymour's daughter, Anne Seymour, to CVV and FM; letters from A. K. Baragwanath of the Museum of the City of New York to CVV (1962)
    - Seymour, Ralph Fletcher, 1924 (Box 145, Folder 1812)
      Includes letter from Alfred A. Knopf to CVV (1924)
    - Shaffer, Van Vechten
      Includes letters from Shaffer's wife, Angevine Shaffer
      - 1932–1961 (Box 146, Folder 1813-1822)
        Includes two letters from Joseph Cassidy to CVV (1947); "Raise a Stein to Gertie" and "A Nude Descends," typescript poems by James Nichols, enclosed with letter from Shaffer to CVV (1949); typescript letter, carbon copy, from Shaffer to William J. Petersen, enclosed with letter from Shaffer to CVV (1952); letter from J. Archer Eggen to Shaffer, with note from Shaffer to CVV (1953); letters from Mary Schuyler to CVV and FM (1953, 1959); letter from Richard B. Hudson to Shaffer (1955); photograph of Shaffer and Angevine Shaffer with five grandsons, enclosed with letter from Angevine to CVV (1956); typed letter, carbon copy, from Shaffer to Joseph and Stewart Alsop, enclosed with letter from Shaffer to CVV (1956); typed transcript of letter from Shaffer to "Polly," sent to CVV (1957)
      - 1962-1971, undated (Box 147, Folder 1823-1824)
        Includes typed letter, carbon copy, from Shaffer to Bruce Kellner, enclosed with note from Shaffer to FM (1969); letter from "Cousin Mary" to CVV and FM (undated)
      - Newspaper clipping, 1964 May 24 (Box 182 (Oversize), Folder 2339)
        Clipping from the Cedar Rapids Gazette, previously enclosed with letter dated 1964 June 18 from Angevine Shaffer to CVV
    - Sharaff, Irene, 1940–1969 (Box 147, Folder 1825)
      Includes letter co-signed Mai-mai [Sze]
    - Shaw Festival, 1967 April 14 (Box 147, Folder 1826)
    - Shawber, Susan Shaffer, 1939-1964, undated (Box 147, Folder 1827-1828)
      Includes letters from Shawber's husband, Lloyd Shawber; three photographs of Susan and Lloyd Shawber and children, enclosed with letter from Lloyd Shawber to CVV and FM (1957)
    - Shawn, Ted, 1956–1964 (Box 147, Folder 1829-1830)
      Includes photograph of Shawn and construction of building at Jacob's Pillow, enclosed with letter from Shawn to CVV (1963)
    - Sheaffer, Louis, 1957–1969 (Box 147, Folder 1831)
    - Sheean, Vincent, 1949–1959 (Box 147, Folder 1832)
      Includes photocopy of typescript draft by CVV of notes to Juanita Hunt and Vincent Sheean [1959], original filed with Juanita Hunt correspondence in JWJ MSS 1050
    - Sheridan, Frank, 1917 November 26 (Box 147, Folder 1833)
    - Sherwin, Louis, 1913–1960 (Box 147, Folder 1834)
    - Short, Hassard, 1926 July 23 (Box 147, Folder 1835)
    - Sickman, L.C.S. (Laurence C.S.), 1936-1950, undated (Box 147, Folder 1836)
    - Sidès, Frédo, 1916; 1921 (Box 147, Folder 1837)
      Letter and postcard to FM
    - Signoret, Simone, 1961; undated (Box 148, Folder 1838)
      Telegram from Signoret to CVV (1961); draft of unsent letter from CVV to Signoret (undated)
    - Sills, Beverly, 1954–1962 (Box 148, Folder 1839)
    - Silverman, Sammy, undated (Box 148, Folder 1840)
      Postcards to FM
    - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1934-1963, undated (Box 148, Folder 1841)
    - Simonson, Lee, 1919; 1937 (Box 148, Folder 1842)
    - Simpson, Helen, 1950 November 26 (Box 148, Folder 1843)
    - Sinclair, Upton, 1911–1936 (Box 148, Folder 1844)
      Newspaper clipping (1911); two printed letters with accompanying printed material (1934, 1936)
    - Singer, Israel Joshua, 1938–1939 (Box 148, Folder 1845)
    - Sjoblom, Jorma Jules, 1958-1964, undated (Box 148, Folder 1846)
      See also: Purdy, James
    - Skouras, Spyros Panagiotes, 1966 February 17 (Box 148, Folder 1847)
    - Slaff, Bertram, 1957–1964 (Box 148, Folder 1848)
      Includes reprint of "A Brief Analysis of the Nature of Psychotherapy," by Slaff and Abram Blau, in New York State Journal of Medicine, October 1957, enclosed with note to CVV and FM (1958)
    - Smart Set, 1917; 1921 (Box 148, Folder 1849)
    - Smith College, 1941 (Box 148, Folder 1850)
      Includes letters from Mina Curtiss and Philip Hofor
    - Smith, Henry Templeton, M.D., 1961–1962 (Box 148, Folder 1851)
    - Smith, Hugh L., 1962–1964 (Box 148, Folder 1852)
    - Smith, Queenie, 1934; 1950 (Box 148, Folder 1853)
      Telegram and letters to FM
    - Smith, T.R. (Thomas Robert), 1921–1934 (Box 148, Folder 1854)
      Includes transcription of night letter sent by Smith and Horace Liveright, enclosed with note from The Colonial Inn, Fairhope, Alabama (1923)
    - Smithkin, Ilona Royce, 1963–1964 (Box 148, Folder 1855)
      Includes letters from Karen B. Katzel to CVV
    - Solomon, Joseph, 1946-1971, undated (Box 148, Folder 1856-1859)
      Includes letters from CVV and FM to Solomon; typed letter, carbon copy, from Charles S. Johnson, Fisk University, to Solomon, enclosed with letter from Solomon to CVV (1950); autograph letter, signed, photostatic copy, of letter to Solomon from Ettie Stettheimer, enclosed with letter from Solomon to CVV and printed copy of part of Stettheimer's will (1955); typescript, carbon copy, list of gifts from Joseph Solomon of the Florine Stettheimer biography by Parker Tyler (1963); copies of third-party letters to Solomon from museums and libraries regarding gifts of the Florine Stettheimer biography and paintings and possible exhibitions of her work (1964); copies of third-party letters regarding permission to publish CVV photographs (1966); third-party letters regarding the estate of Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas (1968-1970); typed letter, carbon copy, from Solomon to Dell Publishing Company regarding permission to publish excerpts from Nigger Heaven (1969); letter from FM to Solomon (1971)
      Letters from CVV and FM to Joseph Solomon, gift of Joseph Solomon, 1979
    - Spaeth, Sigmund, 1928–1940 (Box 148, Folder 1860)
    - Spong, Hilda, 1933 March 7 (Box 148, Folder 1861)
    - Spriggs, Elizabeth, 1953–1956 (Box 149, Folder 1862)
    - Sprinchorn, Carl, 1933–1953 (Box 149, Folder 1863)
    - Stagg, Hunter T. (Hunter Taylor), 1923–1938 (Box 149, Folder 1864-1867)
      See also: Photoduplicated letters from CVV to Stagg in Box 176
    - Stanhope, Frederick, 1916 July 8 (Box 149, Folder 1868)
    - Stanley, Kim, 1958; 1961 (Box 149, Folder 1869)
    - Starr, Frances, 1951-1967, undated (Box 149, Folder 1870)
    - Starr, Muriel, 1913-1948, undated (Box 149, Folder 1871-1872)
      Includes correspondence from CVV to Starr; letter from "A Friend" to FM regarding Starr (1931)
    - Starrett, Vincent, 1920–1963 (Box 149, Folder 1873)
      Includes third-party correspondence and notes relating to Starrett and Arthur Machen (1924); third-party letter regarding a biography of Starrett (1963)
    - Steichen, Edward, 1937 March 17 (Box 149, Folder 1874)
    - Stein, Gertrude
      - Correspondence with CVV
        See also: Photoduplicated letters from Stein to CVV in Box 176
        - 1913–1933 (Box 150, Folder 1875-1883)
          Includes letter from Alfred A. Knopf to CVV (1925); proof of title page for The Making of Americans (1925); letter from CVV to Stein with pencilled page numbers on verso in an unidentified hand (1925); Le Fusil, a children's booklet, inscribed by Stein and Georges Hugnet, enclosed with postcard notes to CVV (1930); cancelled check to Stein from CVV (1931); photographic postcard of CVV and his mother, made from an 1883 photograph, placed by CVV with letter from Stein in which she refers to the photograph (1933); photograph of Picabia and Stein with portrait of Stein by Picabia, with note from Stein to CVV on verso (1932-1933?); postcard drawing of Stein by Picabia with note from Stein to CVV on verso (1933)
        - 1934–1938 (Box 151, Folder 1884-1895)
          Includes letters from Alice B. Toklas to CVV (1934-1935); letter from Ellen Arnold Frank to CVV (1935); letter from unidentified correspondent to Stein, enclosed with letter from Stein to CVV (1935); photographic postcard of Gertrude Stein and Francis Rose, with note from Stein to CVV on verso (1936); four photographs of Frederick Ashton and friends, enclosed with letter from Stein to CVV (1937); "Daniel Webster Eighteen in America: A Play," typescript by Stein, enclosed with letter from Stein to CVV (1937)
        - 1939-1946, undated (Box 152, Folder 1896-1904)